Cauliflower Gratin. 50 min · 8 servings · American
Ingredients: 12. 2 cauliflower heads; 1 cup+ Parmesan and sharp cheddar cheese (mix); 1/2 cup butter; 1 cup panko crumbs
Step 1. Wash and cut cauliflower into bite-size pieces.
Step 2. Boil or steam florets till slight crisp, about 10–15 min.
Step 3. Melt 2–3 tablespoons butter over medium heat; add panko crumbs and stir till slightly toasted.
Step 4. Add 1 tablespoon garlic powder and 1 tablespoon onion powder to the panko crumbs.
Step 5. Place half of the florets into a blender; pulse till smooth.
Step 6. Add cheese, mustard, nutmeg, cayenne, salt, and pepper to the mixture and blend till smooth and creamy. May need to add milk to create a thick sauce.
Step 7. In a 9x9 pan: place whole florets in the pan, pour blended sauce on top, and stir well.
Step 8. Place panko crumbs on top.
Step 9. Bake at 400°F for 30 min+.
You're ready. Use Make It for checkboxes on the page.